Deceased files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Deceased files
2.1.9.2
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1611
- Deceased files, 2.1.9.2
  - Bernt Balchen [includes photograph of Lowell Thomas], 1953; 33 (Box 1611)
    - Note: Envelope that contained photographs, 1
    - [Man and woman standing in front of board that reads "Balchen"], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with a woman], 3
    - [Man standing in front of board full of pictures], 4
  - Prosper Buranelli, circa 1930; 34 (Box 1611)
    - [Portrait of Prosper Buranelli], 1
    - [Portrait of Prosper Buranelli], 2
  - P. A. "Cap" Burtis [includes photograph of Lowell Thomas], 1910; 35 (Box 1611)
    - Dec - 1910; Marian Murphy, Lowell Thomas, Amy Crowell, Aurel Burtis, 1
    - Verso: Dec - 1910; Marian Murphy, Lowell Thomas, Amy Crowell, Aurel Burtis, 1-verso
    - Note: P. A. Burtis 1/30-1969; Dear Tommy: I can't resist sending you this picture. The magnet you have carried all thru the years is proven by this snap-shot. I am wondering where Aurel borrowed the furs. Cap, 2
  - Percy Burton, circa 1940s; 36 (Box 1611)
    - [Portrait of Percy Burton], 1
    - Verso: file Percy Burton, 1-verso
  - Colonel Philip Cochran [includes photograph of Lowell Thomas] [color photograph], 1944; 37 (Box 1611)
    - [Four men mounted on horses, LT second from left], 1
  - Captain Robert Crawford, 1944; 38 (Box 1611)
    - Capt. Bob Crawford, Army Pilot, singing for the men on the Aleutians. 8-28-44, 1
    - Capt. Bob Crawford, Army Pilot, singing for the men on the Aleutians. 8-28-44, 2
    - Note: Capt. Bob Crawford, Army Pilot, singing for the men on the Aleutians. 8-28-44, 3
  - Mary Davis [color photographs], circa 1950 - 1960; 39 (Box 1611)
    - [Three women standing together], 1
    - [Three women standing together], 2
  - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photographs], 1965; 40 (Box 1611)
    - Note: Mrs. G.E. Nicks; Quaker Hill; Pawling, New York; Mary - Dec 29 - 1965, 1
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 2
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 3
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 4
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 5
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 6
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 7
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 8
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 9
    - Mary Davis (headstone) [color photograph], 10
  - Mike Fitzmaurice, undated; 41 (Box 1611)
    - [Mike Fitzmaurice], 1
  - Joe Kirkwood, circa 1953 - 1970; 42 (Box 1611)
    - [Man (Joe Kirkwood?) with giant fish], 1
    - [Man (Joe Kirkwood?) with giant fish], 2
  - Tex O'Reilly, undated; 43 (Box 1611)
    - Tex O'Reilly, Jack Dempsey, Henry Hettling. Taken Oct. 1941 Vet. Hospital Sunmount N.Y, 1
    - Verso: Tex O'Reilly, Jack Dempsey, Henry Hettling. Taken Oct. 1941 Vet. Hospital Sunmount N.Y, 1-verso
  - Leonhard Seppala (dog monument), circa 1968; 44 (Box 1611)
    - [Balto Monument], 1
    - Note: [Written in shorthand], 2
  - Hubert S. Stevens, circa 1944 - 1952; 45 (Box 1611)
    - Note[PDF]: New Electric Sports Timer Shown to Officials and Press, 1
    - Note[PDF]: [Page 1] Olympic Timing Equipment for World Ski Championships Shown to Officials and Press, 2
    - Note[PDF]: [Page 2] At the finish a beam of light is trained on a photo-electric cell, 3
    - Longines Equipment used in timing the World Ski Championships, 4
  - Earl Thacker [color photos of Richard Penhallow's home at Kamuela, Hawaii], 1971; 46 (Box 1611)
    - Note[PDF]: [Letter from Earl M. Thacker to Lowell Thomas] Enclosed are some snapshots of the Richard Penhalloe home at Kamuela on the big island of Hawaii, 1
    - Fireplace of massive flat pahoehoe slabs could be duplicated by slate or other flat rock formations. Bookshelves surround the fireplace creating the appearance that the fireplace is recessed, 2
    - Verso: Fireplace of massive flat pahoehoe slabs could be duplicated by slate or other flat rock formations. Bookshelves surround the fireplace creating the appearance that the fireplace is recessed, 2-verso
    - Another exterior of the bunger [?] land showing the vine covered loggia for shadowing the wall toward sunset, 3
    - Verso: Another exterior of the bunger [?] land showing the vine covered loggia for shadowing the wall toward sunset, 3-verso
    - A corner of the glassed lanai, note the massive log posts and chapiters framing the glass paneled sliding doors, 4
    - Verso: A corner of the glassed lanai, note the massive log posts and chapiters framing the glass paneled sliding doors, 4-verso
    - Showing end of a section of wall by a door jamb, concrete is visible there and door frame is fitted against it., 5
    - Verso: Showing end of a section of wall by a door jamb, concrete is visible there and door frame is fitted against it., 5-verso
    - Exterior detail of a corner of the outside wall. The first step is a trench 2' deep under the wall. This is filled to ground level with poured concrete - called a "curtain wall" or "bearer wall." Then stones are built up one foot at a time, backed by a form of vertical ply-wood 4' high. [?] foot of height; rock work is interrupted, and "sloppy" concrete is bucketed in behind the stones. When this hardens, the stones are held in place by it. When the inside plywood form is removed from the finished stone wall 4' high, it leaves a smooth concrete face which can be concealed by veneer or some other wall cover (matting), 6
    - Verso: Exterior detail of a corner of the outside wall. The first step is a trench 2' deep under the wall. This is filled to ground level with poured concrete - called a "curtain wall" or "bearer wall." Then stones are built up one foot at a time, backed by a form of vertical ply-wood 4' high. [?] foot of height; rock work is interrupted, and "sloppy" concrete is bucketed in behind the stones. When this hardens, the stones are held in place by it. When the inside plywood form is removed from the finished stone wall 4' high, it leaves a smooth concrete face which can be concealed by veneer or some other wall cover (matting), 6-verso
    - Interior of outside wall is: concrete face inside of filled stone for the bottom four feet, and the smooth side of the half-round logs for the top of feet. Matting or veneer inside of concrete face which binds the stones. The interior partitions, of which the wall where the picture hangs, are of vertical 1" x 8" T&G redwood, 7
    - Verso: Interior of outside wall is: concrete face inside of filled stone for the bottom four feet, and the smooth side of the half-round logs for the top of feet. Matting or veneer inside of concrete face which binds the stones. The interior partitions, of which the wall where the picture hangs, are of vertical 1" x 8" T&G redwood, 7-verso
  - Felix von Luckner (headstone), 1967; 47 (Box 1611)
    - Note[PDF]: My dear Tommy, It is first now that I feel able to write you about my beloved Felix, 1
    - [Photograph of Count Felix von Luckner's headstone], 2
  - George Wallace [color photograph], 1966; 48 (Box 1611)
    - Note: "The Explorer"; A Shweizer 3-32 sailplane. All metal aluminum alloy. Wing spread 57 feet. Designed for 10G. Gliding ratio 34 - 1. Most fully instrumented sailplane in the world. Equipped for high altitude and to be used as a platform in an endeavor to detect and identify Clear Air Turbulence. This is a picture of "The Explorer" in test flight. Elmira, New York - August 10, 1966, 1
    - [Two seater airplane in flight], 2